wow this is awesome okay this place is
full all right so good to meet all of
you my name is Travis Connick co-founder
CEO of uber let's see so I do a lot of
speaking because we are we're a
technology company that is we're in the
trenches we're in the cities you know
more than half of our employees are not
in San Francisco I almost I don't even
remember the last time I spoke in San
Francisco in front of an audience every
time I go to speak somewhere right I
look I go on Google and I look at the
roads I look at architecture I look at
cool pictures I can put that are iconic
I'm going to speak in Silicon Valley and
I'm searching Google Images and I can't
find anything and so yeah there you go
it's good to be here all right anyways I
found a little something all right so
guys I'm guessing most people here at
least know what uber is but for those of
you who don't I'm going to go do a sort
of a basic tour just really quick it's
an app on your iPhone that helps you get
a car our motto is everyone's private
driver and so you you open up the app
and you see a bunch of cars that are
near you this is one of San Francisco
cars three minutes away and Jim will
arrive in two minutes he's rated at four
point eight and this is all of course
all screenshots from your app when he
arrives you're told you're notified you
can call the driver of course and if
you're lucky he'll open the door for you
when you're done this is a short trip
$15 that's our minimum in San Francisco
of course we have lower-cost options now
we have something called uber X a couple
days ago we launched taxi in San
Francisco for a lot of folks are like
you're doing tax easier the anti taxi
what are you doing we know what we're
doing but
we'll get to that in just a second all
right so some basics launched in June
2010 so we're we're just over two years
old
we don't own cars we don't employ
drivers a lot of people don't know that
about us I think we we have all these
assets they think that we employ lots of
drivers we don't we have 120 employees
most of which are not in San Francisco
we don't have a marketing spend we're
deployed in 17 cities for some reason
they're 16 here we actually just soft
launched in Sydney a couple days ago
actually yet yesterday Amsterdam is
coming very very shortly and I think
Minneapolis isn't on here we did that a
couple weeks ago so quick numbers
hundreds of thousands of hours driven
per week a very interesting engagement
figure 50% of all the people who have
ever ridden on uber have ridden in the
last 30 days and remember when you ride
your pain so think about commerce think
about a commerce site or a commerce app
or 50% of the people who've ever paid
paid in the last 30 days average person
is paying about 105 dollars a month in
San Francisco it's a bit higher than
that prices are probably a bit too high
I know some of you have felt that sting
we're doing 26 percent month-over-month
growth that's an average over the last
now 16 17 months you go okay well if you
start really low and you can grow really
big but we were pretty big twelve months
ago and if you do 26 percent
month-over-month growth that means in 12
months you're 16 times bigger than you
were 12 months ago so we're growing fast
and in fact September over August was 29
percent month-over-month so I'm going to
tell a little bit about our background
and then hopefully if I have enough time
get into some of the regulatory stuff
which I know none of you guys want to
hear about all right so this you can't
see really well because of all the
lights but it's a romantic shot from the
Eiffel Tower between with me and my
co-founder Garrett camp some of you guys
may know who's the founder of
StumbleUpon
it was in Paris at LeWeb where we came
up with this idea
essentially you know he said look I just
want to push a button and get a ride you
know let's and let's make it a classy
ride and that's kind of how we started
Paris in many ways is a sister city of
San Francisco impossible to get a cab
there so this is something from the past
this is what we call hailing I'm not
sure if you guys have ever done that but
some people actually put their arm out
to get a cab I don't I don't know what's
going on it's a weird thing but this is
what we used to see in San Francisco I
went through that when we first started
actually it wasn't about taking over the
world it wasn't about taking on
corruption in every city around the
world it was actually just about being
baller in San Francisco and the only way
to do it the original idea was let's go
buy 10s classes let's hire 20 drivers
and let's get a parking garage and I'm
like Garrett we're not buying any car
student and we're not signing any lease
on a parking garage but the idea of
pushing a button getting a ride in
within minutes was a magical one and at
the beginning it was lifestyle thing it
was s classes for us and our hundred
friends and so that's where it started
in order to use the app you anybody
could download it but in order to use it
you had us have a special code that I
gave you and pretty soon the inbox was
just getting full of people who wanted
the code because our friends were
telling their friends and then you know
I searched on Google Images my favorite
thing Xplosive viral growth on the
Internet and there you go that was the
best one I could find we have this thing
called God view this is an older version
of God view you can see much more what's
going on today but I can't show you the
new version of God view it's too intense
but this is a screenshot of a Friday
night very soon after we launched maybe
a few weeks or something like that we
had four trips going on at the same time
we were going nuts like there's four
trips there's like we got trips going on
we got to dispatch the Green Line at the
top there that's a dispatch
he shouldn't have his arm up but he does
but he's got it he's got a bill
briefcase which is cool
that's Friday night early on and now
this is 5:00 a.m. on a Monday the
eyeballs by the way you see some
eyeballs
every once in a while in there that's
somebody opening an app so we see when
people open apps that helps us in demand
prediction remember we're a logistics
company or what I'd call it we were
building an urban logistics fabric so
when you do something successful not
everybody's happy and the older the
industry you're tackling the the more
protected it is by government or by
corruption or by both the more they're
going to be upset about what you do
we're making drivers lives a hell of a
lot better they're making a lot more
money they're making ends meet they're
living their American dream and uber is
helping them do that riders are getting
around town much more efficiently I'm
not sure who hurts from this other than
a particular incumbent industry which I
will mention so a few metrics look when
I'm having a bad day I just go to our
overall revenue graph
uh this is a cool trick in Photoshop if
you take that image and you flip it it's
like a smile okay all right that's just
gratuitous okay look we launched in
Sanford oh by the way so this this is
what 26 percent month-over-month growth
looks like and a lot of times when I
show this when I when I do presentations
in cities we every time we launch in a
city we do this big launch event sort of
have some high rollers and people who
really make the city move we sort of pay
our respects to that city and and do a
really nice dinner and and these folks
are always leaning to the left looking
for the axis when we first launched
first of all a lot of people go wow it's
successful that's so obvious I call it
the the hand to the palm to forehead
moment when they learn about uber
they're like I had this idea or I should
have had this idea when we first
launched guys
it wasn't easy getting our angel round
people thought we were crazy limos in
San Francisco what but it took off like
I said and so one of the interesting
things before we went to our series a or
sorry this is actually before our series
be here which we did in November of last
year was is this a one-hit-wonder or not
is this only going to work in San
Francisco because it's so screwed up and
so we started launching in other cities
and this is a Revenue chart on a weekly
it's a weekly window or which you could
think of it's like I'm almost a moving
average blue is San Francisco yellow is
New York this was early on the brown is
Seattle and the green they're Chicago
now obviously we're way past that now
this was like sort of the first hundred
days but what we found is that every
city we were rolling out or just hey we
didn't know if it was going to work
every city we're rolling out got
progressively better our operations side
of the house got very efficient and then
the technology and the number of people
who knew about us when we go in we went
into New York we had a thousand people
with credit cards on file without a car
on the ground
so this wasn't a one-hit wonder and so
we just started launching a ton of
cities we have this double rainbow of
metrics what does it mean remember as
liquidity goes up this is you know
people in the marketplace who are
building a marketplace know what
liquidity means it means demand and
supply go up together if they don't you
have a marketplace in our world as
liquidity goes up the quality of the
experience goes up and it dramatically
right so our average pickup times in San
Francisco are two minutes and 45 seconds
when we first started in New York we're
like 12 minute average pickup times and
let me tell you you don't want to be
delivering 12 minute pickup times to New
Yorkers they will kick your ass
so as it gets better now we're right
around five minutes in New York and
that's kind of when they lose their
minds as more people use it you go from
the core user base to bigger the
engagement actually gets deeper the
number of rides per Rider per month
actually go up as we expand as a cool
cohort graph but who cares all right the
bottom line is that 50% of the people
who've ever used still use and we've
seen that from the beginning this is an
interesting one this is San Francisco
indexed revenue so we're getting there's
lots of town cars in San Francisco right
the number of town cars that they were
in San Francisco before we got there was
600 there are now more cars dedicated to
Eber then there were town cars in San
Francisco when we got there and so
you're like well this thing is going to
slow down this train is going to slow
down at some point we indexed San
Francisco revenue from last year July
1st through the end of the year and
looked at this year July 1st to where we
are now and it's tracking almost
identical so it's not slowing down
anytime soon and when you're talking
about for a particular city 20 percent
month-over-month it growth that's that's
really big growth especially when you're
when the the numbers are getting big so
on the operations side I think a lot of
us are techies you know I'm an engineer
by
meaning we know what product managers
are we know what that means but when
you're on the ground when your
technology touches people and it touches
cities what you have to do is have
process managers process managers are
similar product managers they manage the
process that people do versus machines
and the roadmap for product has to
dovetail with the roadmap for process
because anytime we change anything that
happens in a car that's got to change
the tech and vice versa so there's
really interesting Road mapping
processes that we go through come on
this is supposed to be a picture of
Europe we're rolling out very big in
Europe right now so getting the
operational expertise and I think this
just isn't talked a lot about in
startups is the operation side of the
business I think a lot of e-commerce
companies see that we see it on a very
deep level because of you know the
rubber is actually meeting the road but
getting teams ready to roll out in
Europe is something we've been spending
time where in Paris in London right now
like I said we're going to be an
Amsterdam very soon and there's a whole
host of other cities that were that are
lined up in Europe and that's going to
be a big push end of this year all the
way into the first half of next year we
have somebody in Asia ready to go and
Sydney's sort of our first city in Asia
pack and I can't wait to go to the
launch party okay all right so quality
and choice it was really interesting
right we we had this high-end thing it's
cost about 50 percent more than a cab
and everybody said oh that's high-end
and everybody goes wow I'm going to do a
low-cost uber there's like a few
companies out there I can't remember
their names that decide they're going to
be a low-cost - when they clone our app
you know they flatter us by basically
stealing all the pixels and copying them
over to their app uber fYI Buber is
going to be a low-cost uber but it's
about quality and choice and what we see
when we lo when we roll out a low-cost
option what we see is that
actually engagement gets deeper because
people have choice they don't have to
always get the expensive thing so they
start using it more often people who
maybe wouldn't start with the black card
products start with taxi or what we call
uber X and then it's date night and they
want to prove you know they want to
impress their lady or they just need a
comfortable ride and it it goes from
there so this was a little choice of
beautiful thing let's keep moving
taxi we did in Chicago in April we now
have a few cities we're in Boston
Toronto Chicago San Francisco we were in
New York over not anymore don't get me
started
fair enough we'll get to that at the end
we did uberx which is sort of like a
low-end uber where and we did this in
July in San Francisco in New York and
that's where it's basically 30% cheaper
all hybrid fleet at least in SF where
we're starting to diversify a little bit
out of hybrids because we can't get the
partners to buy cars fast enough but the
thing is is you push a button and a car
appears in five minutes and that feels
magical but how you make that happen is
actually very complex so we have a math
department here there I like to tell
them I say look guys you're in charge of
our margins right because they need to
get the pickup times really low but the
utilization really high how do you do
that right well you do that through a
lot of math but let's start with our
math department okay that's not my math
department but we have two nuclear
physicists on staff a computational
neuroscientist a machine learning expert
and a few other guys there they're
killing it and some of the things they
do they do demand prediction congestion
prediction supply matching supply
positioning smart dispatch algorithms
dynamic pricing Friday and Saturday
night are special nights we sometimes
get really big waves of demand that you
can't really get enough cars to do
anything about so you have a marketplace
oriented sort of dynamic
pricing element that clears the market
it gets more cars on the road and in
sort of lassos in sort of uncontrollable
demand you can't see these pictures
really well because of the lights but
they're pretty these are some heat maps
of cities this is DC right here but you
you guys probably can't see it this is
Manhattan can't you tell
anyways these are useless I'll just keep
going okay all right this right here is
what drivers see this is our supply
positioning so in our company when mass
goes operational that becomes how am i
doing on time by the way I have no
timing here eight minutes left all right
hey minutes left all right this is going
to suck all right all right so supply
positioning right we have a heat map of
demand but I can basically we're
predicting demand twenty minutes ahead
of time the problem is is that if I gave
the heat map to drivers right they'll
all go to the same spot and then that'll
be bad for a lot of people who aren't in
that hot spot so we do is we say here's
the heat map of demand or prediction for
20 minutes ahead time but where is the
supply right now that's anti heat that
sucks the heat out of the map what's
left over is residual heat under serve
demand and we do that on a neighborhood
by neighborhood basis will ultimately go
continuous on it the math is very tricky
and complex and computationally
intensive but that gives you a sense of
some of the things we do that's in-car
you don't see it because once you get in
the car he's on trip and he doesn't see
that map anymore dynamic pricing I
talked a little bit about that already
we have one of our nuclear physicists
guys is a big San Francisco Giants fan
clearly we have to look at events in the
city because that affects the man in a
big way when the Giants play of course
demand is huge when the Giants win it's
much huger than when they lose as people
want to go out in style you know they
want to go the bars they're just feeling
good actually what's interesting is in
Boston when they lose when the Red Sox
lose we actually have bigger demand
no joke here's what's really interesting
it's not enough to make money yet I just
gave away the punchline but basically
that huge uptick in demand one that when
a giant San Francisco Giants win starts
about three hours before the game begins
uber Vegas is going to take on a whole
new meaning okay so I'm going to really
speed through here and I've sucked
because there's so much cool regulatory
stuff I could have talked about but
giving riders high fives
look transportations and thought of as a
boring space it's boring well until you
push a button a car magically appears
but we basically have lots of people who
love us and how do we get them to tell
that story over and over again give them
an excuse to tell the uber story so we
do a lot of creative things I think a
lot of you guys have seen that but look
Valentine's Day we distribute tens of
thousands of roses to thousands of
drivers every girl who got in a car
after 4 p.m. was handed a rose by the
driver that's a strong move fellas
I call it I call this scaling romance
okay on Presidents Day in DC we did what
we call an uber Kade okay
Escalade Town Car Escalade American
flags all the way down one out of every
20 people that push the button and uber
Kade rolls up the druk the driver the
driver has an earpiece that makes them
look like Secret Service and as you're
driving through town kids are like
waving they're like knocking on the
window we did something in we did
something in South by Southwest
we got pedicabs because you don't do a
town car in South white that's just
douchey like don't do that but a pedicab
let's do this right so we did that
that's cool 100 pedicabs you push a
button pedicab takes you wherever you
want to go but we took ten of those
petty cabs and we outfitted them with
these containers that could hold Texas
barbecue so we did on demand Texas
barbecue you push the button and a cow
would come to you on the map we did ice
cream in July and every time we roll out
a city we do what's called rider zero
the first person to get in an uber when
we soft-launched
it used to be an organic thing that just
happened and then the my city team
started getting excited about it this is
Edward Norton taking the first we were
in Los Angeles to go surfing so we give
riders high-fives but we give drivers
hugs and that's because look the riders
you know they date night goes well they
get to their business meeting on time or
they're not stranded a certain part of
town but for a driver who's scrapping
who maybe has a few hours in the morning
and one or two hours in the evening or
in the afternoon booked filling out that
time with a consistent revenue stream
helps him make ends meet and so you go
from just barely making ends meet to
really making a living and then
investing in your business we have
drivers who
from one car to 15 each of those cars
grossing more than a hundred grand a
year so these guys are living their
American dream
this is riad he actually was hustling
one of our engineers early on our
engineers were getting unlimited uber
he's like I got it were cool but why
don't you come join you bur he did he's
the highest performing driver on the
system he makes twenty or thirty percent
more per hour
I was productive driver on the system
than all the other drivers he also the
highest rated driver we still haven't
figured out how he does what he does he
now has five cars on the system he
recently had his firstborn son named his
son after our engineer that's not funny
like that's for real all right
this is Hani he's a comedian been in the
city for about 25 years he or he thinks
of himself as a comedian every time I
get in the car he tells me used to be a
Chippendales dancer this is Steve Aziz
and guys just somebody signal when I'm
running out of time I have no idea I'll
go over and spend an hour up here if you
let me two minutes okay all right Steve
Aziz has 15 or sorry 20 cars on the
system
he started with one he's got five kids
told me out of six going and six on the
way that's funny I said Steve six kids
you're crazy what are you doing dude
that's nuts
you got a business to run he's like I
got I got to keep the uber that we were
FLE growing
his son there doesn't look too happy to
be part of the uber fleet well I could
talk about regulation I'd spend a couple
minutes the bottom line is and I can't
go through a bunch of slides because I
really don't have the time well I don't
know let's just go until somebody stop
saying this is a New York City medallion
that's the license to basically own and
operate a single taxi in New York the
number of taxis or medallions in New
York it's the blue bar there the dark
blue it's basically been flat since 1946
the same number of taxis that were in
the city in 1946 is the same number of
taxis that are out there today that
value of that Medina is worth about a
million dollars a pop there are 13,000
medallions in the city of New York so
you have 13 billion dollars directed at
keeping uber from being successful DC we
had a really interesting situation
we went there by the way we were as far
as we could tell
we were totally legal White Glove legal
nicest laws in the country in terms of
sedans in DC but DC taxi commissioner
goes out there and says ubers not legal
because they charge by time and distance
and let's just say that was real why is
charging by distance evil I don't
understand I don't get it but he said
look you're charging my time and
distance you're not allowed well we
looked at the law law says sedan a for
hire vehicle designed to carry fewer
than six passengers which charges with a
service on the basis of time and mileage
like what are you talking about is going
in public forms Washington Post etc we
go the Attorney General in the District
of Columbia and that's what he tells us
so when you read about the crazy stuff
we're doing in the cities and I've got
to close this down because I'm - that
somebody's going to have the hook and
they're going to take me off here but
when you read about the crazy stuff that
we're doing in the cities know that it
is corrupt out there know that we are
highly highly disruptive in what you
read in the papers isn't always true and
the bottom line is that in order to be
in this business in order to be this
disruptive to what's going on you have
to have you have to be willing to to
fight and you have to not be it you
can't be shy so that gives you a little
bit about it basically they try to put a
floor on our prices I'll leave it at
this one this last one here they put a
floor on our prices try to pass what
they call the uber amendment make our
prices five times out of a taxi they
rolled the amendment out July 10th
there's a Monday at a July 9th the vote
on the bill is the tenth sorry they put
the bill out on the night that was a
Monday at 4:00 p.m. to vote on at 11:00
a.m. the next day 18 hours most of which
are going to be sleeping I wrote an
email to our consumers letting know that
they were about to do this and by the
way the rationale was to ensure that
basically we don't compete if a CEO of a
company told said something like this
they'd be in jail but if you corrupt
your politicians and then push those
laws down it's totally legal anyways we
did something called life liberty and
the pursuit of Urbanus uber DC love is a
hashtag 18 hours later we had 50,000
original emails these weren't robo
emails that went to City Council people
telling them not to vote for it
37,000 tweets 104 million social media
impressions and we won and
as you might imagine there wasn't a lot
of sleep during that time but it was so
short it maybe didn't matter so anyways
guys I think the bottom line I've got so
much stuff Vegas by the way gambling and
prostitution illegal in Vegas but Hoover
is not I got so much stuff I probably
have to end this I'll just end with just
a couple more slides here guys and I'm
sorry about this
look technology is wiring up the core
services in city life right
Airbnb us a bunch of other companies
they're changing not just tech not just
your twitter app they're changing how
you live but that change used to happen
over decades it's not happening over
months quality of life is not red it's
not blue it's just people right cities
that resist are going to feel backwards
and their cities were not in they feel
backwards all right a lot of our
customers who are used to this go to
other cities it doesn't work so I asked
the mayor's what are you protecting who
are you protecting now and realize they
just don't even realize that they're
protecting they think the taxi industry
they think drivers know you're actually
screwing over drivers so cities need
transportation alternatives but they
need modern accountable convenient
stylish and efficient ones we're out
there in a city near you guys and look I
appreciate being here is a lot of fun
and thank you